right one of the dumbest arguments we
ever got into was we were watching a
basketball game and in the third quarter
lebron james had missed a dunk he looked
over at me and he goes
[Music]
lebron james sucks
i don't know how much you all know about
lebron james
well lebron james got drafted out of
high school at 17 years old he was the
number one overall pick in the nba draft
he signed a 95 million dollar contract
with nike three-time nba champion
four-time league mvp youngest player to
score 35 000 points ever
my friend daryl has failed his driver's
test four times
four
whole times daryl sucks okay
yeah
i didn't even know you got to take the
test four times
i thought after you failed the second
time they're like hey you know what
here's a 50 uber credit you don't get to
drive anymore
you're a danger to society
i do believe in being positive man you
gotta look on the right side i actually
did live in a wheelchair for a long time
but i tried to be positive then too like
i tried that wheelchair basketball
i was horrible
everybody else goes down on a fast break
and i'm just going in circles
but you gotta stick with it pilgrim
because eventually i started beating
every one of those guys you know once i
learned to walk again
defense
no i didn't really do that you know but
i did volunteer to be the ref right
they didn't let me
apparently i was too one-sided
[Laughter]
all right about the sports i played
sports i wanted them to play sports too
i know y'all are thinking you
thing you did not but i play basketball
thank you
i need that
um
it was the early 80s
when i played
and uh i had really big hair
i used to hot roll my hair
to play ball
we all did
okay so and i'm from such a little bitty
farming community and it's 500 people in
middle tennessee and we didn't know what
waterproof mascara was so by the end of
my games i looked like
say if tammy wanted alice cooper had a
child together
i was a forward sometimes i had to be
the center if mary down had to take her
baby to the health department i've had
so much fun with you guys you guys are
wonderful people this is his dream come
true to get to come do comedy for people
like you guys is going well and i'm
thankful that this this dream is working
out then better than my previous dream
uh all throughout my whole life
my dream was to play in the nba and
that wasn't a joke that was for real
i'm pouring my heart out to you people
i know why you're laughing so let's just
talk about it
there's not a lot of five foot five guys
like me in professional basketball
here's the you know everybody wants to
make fun of the short guy until your
kids won't come down from the play place
then we're everybody's best friend
oh little gavin won't come down will he
[Applause]
the same gavin you were offering me his
old clothes a second ago okay
i was watching
this young lady be interviewed on tv the
other day on some show and they were
interviewing her because she came up
with this machine young lady 24 years
old she came over this machine and what
it did
is it filtered dirty water into clean
drinking water quickly and cheaply it
looked like a little plastic box and
they sent these things all over the
world to these poor countries and they
said because of her invention they saved
thousands of lives
and they said how did you come up with
this idea and she's like oh is this on
my couch daydreaming
and it came to me
what
that is incredible that she could come
up with something like that just on her
couch because that it made me feel
terrible
because the other day i was on my
couch and for two hours
i thought to myself
how many people
would have to die
before i was the greatest basketball
player on earth
i gave that serious thought for two
hours
and at the end of the two hours i
concluded that you know
be a lot
like there'd be so many dead people at
that point that you know
it wouldn't be fun to be the best
basketball player
because noah would care you know
because of the tragedy
i mean no one would care about like hey
you guys want to get a game and i know
brenda we're trying to rebuild maybe
should pick up a shovel and help us with
this rebuild
[Music]
i'm sorry i don't know anything about
shovels or building but you just let me
know if you need any help getting
buckets
because i'm the best
i'm the best that's left
i wanna uh i like to see a jazz game
while i'm here maybe someone give me
some jazz tickets
anybody basketball fans out there
you know i like professional basketball
because those athletes are the least in
contact with reality
i like when a seven foot tall player
dunks the basketball no one's guarding
him he starts celebrating like he did
something special
you are seven foot tall sir that's the
same skill level as me flushing a toilet
i mean i forget about a nice flush but i
walk away keep it cool
i let my stats speak for themselves
well you know i played of course i
played no grade school basketball teams
complete without a tall gangly
uncoordinated crybaby
hey coach it's me johnny you want to put
me in
no
good eye coach
good eye
i don't know how it worked at your
school at my school you had to try out
for the team you want to be on you know
they had different levels of teams
everybody wanted to be on the a team a
team had all the cool kids all the star
athletes right
then there was the beat team
b team had a couple kids in wheelchairs
a bunch of blind kids
kid without a head
yeah he was blind too
i was on the c team
yeah our team name was
johnny and phil
i wasn't even a starter
so i got to name my son and i've always
been a big fan of michael jordan huge
fan watched all his games growing up
right had the air jordan sneakers in
fact these are the retro 11 bred low air
jordans thank you very much
yeah
pretty cool anyway uh so my son's name
is basketball shoe
my kids got it too easy that's a problem
too easy
but i mean two not the word two but the
number two too easy cause they got that
two-parent love
true parent love is overrated i'm sorry
to say that
it is
i know it's great to have both parents
but not when you're trying to raise an
athlete
[Laughter]
i guess my kids are pretty good in
basketball but they never work on their
game cause they got that two-parent love
they come home they got air conditioning
heating cover full of food
video games like why don't you guys go
outside and work on your game it's too
hot out there dad it's comfortable in
here
meanwhile that single parent kid who
doesn't know who his father is hates his
home life
mother's always yelling at him he's
always hungry so he's never at home
instead he's at the park working on his
game six hours a day and he is going to
destroy my kids
this is why i grab my kids and totem
this is why i'm leaving your mom
you're crying why are you leaving us
cause you won't practice i don't know
what else to do
my hands are tied
maybe if you see me every other weekend
you get your act together
anyway so i grew up in this small town
in northern california and not a very
diverse town i know you can't imagine
that here but uh
yeah
don't look around i was um
i was the only caucasian in an all-white
neighborhood growing up so i know
i know how it can be it can be tough
we wanted to play pick up basketball but
all we had were referees it was
difficult and i'm not saying it's easy
we walk out of the restaurant you're not
gonna believe it a black lives matter
rally broke out
right there
i don't even know it was a rally that
day i had no clue i was unprepared i
didn't get an email i'm like oh man i'm
not not ready for the rally
me and my free dog are walking through
at a rally i
i looked at him i was like hey you
biting anybody at this rally back to the
green mile you go
so we're walking through
and uh black lives matter rally is
always interested in utah by the way
because there are never any black people
there
um
it's white people on my behalf i had
no idea y'all took up the cards
protesting on behalf of people
that will never be here
it's a nice move
i walked in it was like i was a
celebrity it was oh my gosh is that
karma malone
yes it is carmelo
and uh i am the mailman i started
signing autographs i'm like mailman 32
yeah i didn't want to you know let these
native people down you know what i mean
not
not everybody gets to meet their hero
they're starting autographs
i saw a white dude do a backflip i'm
like oh my goodness what part of the
struggle is that
he walked up black lives matter bro
hit me with two finger guns black lives
matter bro i'm like you almost
hypothetically killed me dawg
that is the most offended i've been all
day
and carl malone respect me
[Music]
walking through
i wanted to play professional basketball
that's not the joke
i'm i'm from north carolina so i went i
went to school on a place called tobacco
road i'm a north carolina state wolf
pack graduate so i went to a pretty big
basketball area as a kid and growing up
that's all i wanted to do and i know i
don't look i played up high school
basketball that's the only impression i
do on my show 16. me on the high school
basketball team this is me 1991 high
school basketball team me
high school basketball team ready go
[Music]
[Applause]
every once in a while you're here
spammer get caught you get in the game i
get it that's ball game
oh man
i uh i did play basketball played
college basketball we got any basketball
fans
[Applause]
yeah i played i was a full disclosure i
was a walk-on which means i had front
row seats and matching jerseys but
had some good stats though while i was
on the team had some good stats cpm
claps per minute good job guys
oh man i wish i could jump like
uh i was on the team for a year and a
half so for a year and a half my name
was seth with an f
uh because that's how black guys say
seth for some reason
[Laughter]
didn't know what to make of that i was
talking to one of my teammates one day
and he's just like massa you a thug i'm
like
hold on you just said thug that has a th
in it
that means you could say my name right
this whole time you just choose not to
for some reason
he's like man shut up seth
talk to me like that on my birthday
[Laughter]
i'm cool with it i'm cool with it but
the the downside to getting older is
that you you get a point you get to a
point where you realize your mind
and body aren't always on the same page
oh my god oh my god that's where i'm at
now you know what i'm saying that's a
hard place for dudes to be i was playing
basketball i went to block a shot
because my mind
said ty go block that shot you can block
that shot when the block was shot my
body was like hey
where you going
[Music]
you didn't check with us about blocking
the shot
what we can do is let you twist the
ankle
and uh hyperventilate we got you covered
on that
because i play ball with these 20 year
olds and i don't know why it's dumb it's
dumb because first of all the motivation
of a 20 year old in the gym way
different than mine
way different than mine they walk in the
gym they working on being the next
lebron they working on being the next
kobe i'm working on my cholesterol
i had a doughnut last night bro that's
all i'm just trying to work it off it's
all it is
trying to sweat it out dude ain't trying
to
and trying to win no championships in
here okay
and the recovery time recovery time of a
20 year old miraculous
miraculous they could twist their ankle
put a piece of gum on it and be cool
one kid last week broke his arm broke
his arm
ripped it off grew another one
[Laughter]
i'm like same tattoo and everything
[Music]
and one thing i wish i knew before i had
kids was a parental peer pressure
because we get tricked into doing stuff
we don't have to do i got tricked into
coaching my kids second grade basketball
team
nobody wants that job
nobody wants that job if there's a guy
who's like i'll do it i'll do it i'm
just saying double check and make sure
that that guy brought a kid okay
i was doing that for 10 weeks this guy
came up to me he's like hey coach
i'm aiden's dead and uh we got a problem
i'm like yeah man we do have a problem
because i had no idea there was a kid
named aiden on this team
i didn't learn any of their names i
learned a very important lesson though i
learned
that every 90 year old guy with his
pants up to his armpits
that guy just coached too many youth
sports because i showed up every single
father had their shirt tucked in i'm
talking polo tank top camo i'm like oh
is this the dress code for fatherhood
okay
is this what authority looks like to a
second grader here we go look at me i'm
in charge
and next thing you know i'm walking back
and forth with all these other dads like
hey buddy tie your shoes
ty your shoes come on man come on
pass the ball
ramble you have to dribble are you
kidding me
by the end of this game i was everything
i hated as a child
i was just like another crazy old man
these kids wouldn't listen to me because
my belt loops were touching my nipples
my wife has a friend that's really
fashionable
and she was like hey you've lost some
weight you should uh she wears some
tighter pants i'm like not on stage i
shouldn't uh
yeah man that getting older sneaks up on
you though right i uh i had a wake-up
call for how old i am recently
i was playing pick-up basketball at a
park and these young guys showed up one
of them bumps into me my whole life
somebody bumps into me in sports they're
like my bad you good you good this young
guy bumped into me and he's like sir are
you all right
he's like man i'm sir are you all right
old i had no idea
worst part was i was not all right at
all
i was limping out of that park like
that'll be okay later someday probably
maybe i don't know my wife's got
ointments we'll figure it out
[Music]
but if you follow sports you know
there's a lot more white coaches than
black coaches even though a lot more
professional athletes are black than
white and it's finally changing finally
improving and people always said it's
racism it's prejudice that's why there's
so many more white coaches for so long
as opposed to black coaches and it's not
racism or prejudice the reason for so
many more white coaches for so long is
because growing up as a white athlete we
spend a lot more time on the sidelines
than black athletes
so that by the time we retire it's like
oh yeah i've seen the game from this
perspective yeah
i know exactly what i'm looking at
yeah he's gonna come around he comes
under i've been over here my whole life
oh yeah
look at my footprints from childhood
yeah
uh age five seven nine eleven thirteen
i've never been on that side what's it
like over there oh my ankle oh okay oh
oh okay my ankle
[Music]
white coaches know how to win with less
black coaches sometimes have
expectations that are too high right
those who can't teach those who can
can't teach michael jordan could never
coach basketball he'd be like come on
guys why is nobody dunking from the free
throw line all right
these are fundamentals we talk about
this every day in practice just jump
over all five guys every time
[Music]
jump out there stay up there you know
there's nothing going on down here
win six championships in eight years
play a second professional sport get
your own shoe and clothing line starting
a movie with bugs bunny
it's the pyramid of success i don't get
it with you guys right
played baseball growing up did you know
that the dimensions to a baseball field
are just whatever
it's completely true every major league
baseball field is different the
infield's always the same
90 feet to each base but the outfield
fence they just make it up
this is 100 percent sure to hit a home
run in fenway park boston red sox have
got to hit that ball 302 feet
houston astros on the other hand minute
maid park they have to hit the ball 436
feet
that's a 45 difference
and no one ever talks about it like
maybe there's a reason why the red sox
have been to 13 world series
and the astrals were swept in one
it's like hey guys there's no rule
moving your fence
make it easier on yourselves
a 45 difference can you imagine if any
other sport just decided to start doing
that there would be an uproar right
you see that excited nba coach hey great
news guys are playing in chicago this
week the rooms they're only five and a
half feet tall
and i think about our wedding day all
the time to this day i'll never forget
it i was up at the altar you know
everybody's looking at me i was wearing
this
[Music]
church doors open up there she is the
most beautiful i've ever seen her
and she makes her way all the way up to
the altar
she gets this close to my face
and she whispers to me something i'll
never forget
she says
why
aren't
you crying
excuse me
why
aren't
you
crying
i'm happy
no happiest day of our life and friends
family jesus we're all here so
can we talk about this any other time
than right now
if this was the happiest day of your
life
you'd be crying
i'm starting to tear up a little bit
right now
you know from the fear in my bones
and the knowledge i'm about to sign a
life contract
with what i'm finding out to be
an emotional dictator
[Music]
i have a flight response right now but
you're kind of in the way
we fast forward a few years
and the cleveland cavaliers when the
nba championship
bringing my city of cleveland
its first title
in 975
000 years
and i am crying my eyes out
i am
inconsolable
i'm saying outrageous things
things like this is the literal best day
of my life
or
i will never be as happy as i am right
now
in this moment
and
what other time in my life was ever this
happy
nothing nothing comes to mind
total blank
and that's when i feel a cold stare
right here
it's her
[Laughter]
she's angry
she says best day of your life
huh
i said you're right it is it is
lebron james average and triple double
through seven games
do you have any idea how hard that is to
do
with that playoff schedule in an 82 game
regular season
we overcame
a to one deficit for the first time in
all of nba history why aren't you crying
[Music]
and that's what true love is ladies and
gentlemen
don't start don't start now don't start
now
don't fake it